# Eric Zachary Ryder Sr. Architect

831-383-8887 eric@ryderez.com

## Industry, Application Qualification Summary

Twenty five years overall experience in systems related positions, including 14 years EMC-Documentum Consulting; 5 years Technical Support; 9 years in Pre-Sales Support. I have been in customer-facing roles for most of my career. As an Architect for EMC-Documentum, I specialized in database and application tuning, (Oracle and SQL Server), and was considered the "go to" resource for anything database related nationally. I am a people person and a troubleshooter, with excellent professional references, and have been in well over 100 Fortune 1,000 companies, as well as state and federal government entities, (IRS, US Patent Office, US Army, etc). I am a quick study and have a personality that is suited for consulting; technically astute, yet politically sensitive and personable.

Strong verbal, written, and troubleshooting skills.

## Project Experience

 Focus on Documentum architecture, infrastructure planning and implementation, system performance tuning, database tuning and query optimization, (Oracle, SQL Server), installations, upgrades/migrations, distributed architecture, LDAP, small utility script programming in UNIX, Reveille Software monitoring, and system administration.

### Recent Projects

- PG&E: Part of Infrastructure Team responsible for design, install, and tuning of Dev, Test, QA, and Production environments utilizing Documentum Content Server 6.7 SP1 stack, Oracle 11, RedHat, LDAP, SiteMinder, Apache, xPlore 1.2, High Availability, Load Balancing, and Disaster Recovery.
- Discover Financial Services: Designed and implemented a major upgrade and migration of 800 million object, Oracle 11, repository from Solaris to RHEL, while minimizing down-time to one weekend.
- FDIC and GSA: Performed thorough analysis of the entire enterprise deployment to quantify improvements for performance and overall usability. (Healthcheck)

### **Employers**

### Reveille Software

Documentum Consultant, Sales August, 2011 – Present

Pre and post Sales activities, including demo's, webinars, marketing collateral, and implementing pilot POC's of Reveille software.

• EMC-Documentum, Inc.

Sr. Architect, Professional Services March, 2001 – May, 2012

April 10, 2013 Page 1 of 2

Performance tuning, repository database design, capacity planning, server-side systems architecture for Linux, UNIX, and Windows OS. Load balancing design, distributed content architecture, upgrade planning and implementation for high volume 24x7 enterprise repositories, data migration planning and implementation, enterprise-wide implementation health-check, focused on Oracle and SQL Server.

#### gForce, Inc.

Director, Professional Services October, 1999 – March, 2001

Built a team of 12 consultants to implement web-based training software solution to Fortune 500 companies. This was a startup company, so many hats were worn; Customer Support; pre-Sales and Services Support, installations, upgrades, troubleshooting, QA, etcetera.

#### • EMC-Documentum, Inc.

Sr. Consultant, Professional Services April, 1997 – October, 1999 Technical Support March, 1995 – April, 1997

Performance Tuning expert for Oracle, Sybase, and SQL Server based implementations. While in Tech Support, specialized in UNIX related support calls, as well as other server issues related to upgrades, performance, installs, etcetera.

#### Xerox, Inc.

Systems Engineer, GIS CAD Sales October, 1986 – February, 1995 Technical Support Engineer February, 1984 – October, 1986

Pre-Sales support. Demo's, training, installs, and post-Sales support for a 2-D CAD GIS mapping system software suite, utilizing a Sybase backend.

## Academic Background

- University of California Berkeley (extension). Technical marketing for Application Engineers, UNIX shell programming, Visual Basic Programming, (4.0).
- Other Courses: Oracle Performance Tuning, Sun Microsystems:
  Advanced Systems Administration. Dan McBride Sales Seminars.
  Xerox: Leadership Through Quality; various courses in management,
  programming, and sales. Documentum: Web Customization, Technical
  Fundamentals for Documentum, Documentum System Administration I
  and II, Application Development, Intro to IBM DB2.
- Bryant College: Bachelor of Business Administration

References and more detailed information available online at <a href="http://ryderez.com/consulting">http://ryderez.com/consulting</a>

April 10, 2013 Page 2 of 2